<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>SWGRealms - Managed Star Wars Galaxies Hosting</title>
    <subtitle>Managed hosting platform for Star Wars Galaxies communities. Focus on building great experiences, not managing servers.</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.swgrealms.com/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.swgrealms.com"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2025-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.swgrealms.com/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Developer Update 003 - User migration and Developer Interview</title>
        <published>2025-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.swgrealms.com/updates/developer-update-003-user-migration-developer-interview/"/>
        <id>https://www.swgrealms.com/updates/developer-update-003-user-migration-developer-interview/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://www.swgrealms.com/updates/developer-update-003-user-migration-developer-interview/">&lt;p&gt;Since our last update on authentication, we&#x27;ve been hard at work building the core systems that will power SWGRealms. This update focuses on two critical areas: keeping communities safe through intelligent content moderation, and establishing the technical foundation that will support a universe of galaxies.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;user-migration-made-simple&quot;&gt;User Migration Made Simple&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#x27;ve completed the user migration system that lets existing SWGEmu community members join SWGRealms while preserving their community history. Your veteran status, forum activity, and community identity all carry forward seamlessly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two Easy Ways to Join:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SWGEmu Forum Integration&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Log into your SWGEmu forums account and visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.swgemu.com&#x2F;registration&#x2F;swgrealms&#x2F;&quot;&gt;swgemu.com&#x2F;registration&#x2F;swgrealms&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for one-click account creation. This secure process:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uses your existing SWGEmu username and email&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sends a temporary password to your registered email&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lets you set a new SWGRealms-specific password&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keeps your original SWGEmu account completely unchanged&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Direct Login&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.swgrealms.com&#x2F;login&#x2F;&quot;&gt;swgrealms.com&#x2F;login&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and sign in with your existing SWGEmu username and password. You&#x27;ll be required to change your SWGRealms password (your SWGEmu password remains unchanged) and can login when complete.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both methods require access to your SWGEmu email account and preserve your community history and veteran status while maintaining the security of your original SWGEmu account. If you don&#x27;t have access to your SWGEmu email, contact SWGEmu support to update it first.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;developer-interview&quot;&gt;Developer Interview&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those interested in a deeper dive into the vision and technical details behind SWGRealms, I recently did an extensive 90-minute interview covering:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My background and motivation for this project&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The origin story and philosophy behind SWGRealms&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multi-accounting policies and galaxy owner flexibility&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AI-powered NPCs and content moderation possibilities&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cross-server features like tells and character transfers&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Migration paths for existing servers and their communities&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why this unifies rather than fragments the community&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;zhA1ij3vIE4&quot;&gt;watch the full interview here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to learn more about the motivations and long-term goals for the project.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;community-safety-first&quot;&gt;Community Safety First&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online gaming communities thrive when players feel safe to express themselves and build friendships. Unfortunately, toxic behavior, spam, and inappropriate content can quickly destroy the welcoming atmosphere that makes Star Wars Galaxies communities special.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than leaving each galaxy owner to handle moderation alone, SWGRealms now includes an intelligent content moderation system that works behind the scenes to keep communities healthy:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automatic Detection&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Harmful content is identified and flagged before it reaches other players&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Learning&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The system gets better over time by learning from community patterns&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Galaxy Owner Control&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Each galaxy can set their own community standards and moderation preferences&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transparent Process&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Players understand what happened and why, with clear appeals processes&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of it like having a helpful community moderator who never sleeps, never has a bad day, and consistently applies your community&#x27;s standards fairly to everyone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;seamless-user-experience&quot;&gt;Seamless User Experience&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For players, this all happens invisibly. You sign in, join your favorite galaxy, and play - just like you always have. The difference is that toxic players and spam are filtered out before they can disrupt your experience, letting you focus on the adventures and friendships that make SWG special.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Galaxy owners get powerful tools to shape their community culture without spending hours manually reviewing every forum post or in-game message. You set the standards, and the system helps enforce them consistently.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;building-for-the-long-term&quot;&gt;Building for the Long Term&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behind the scenes, we&#x27;ve been establishing the technical foundation that will support SWGRealms as it grows from a handful of beta galaxies to potentially a universe of thriving communities.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What This Means for You:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reliable Performance&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Your galaxy will run smoothly even as the platform grows&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Protection&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Your community data is secure and properly backed up&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy Migration&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Moving your existing SWGEmu community to SWGRealms is straightforward&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Future Features&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: New capabilities can be added without disrupting existing galaxies&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;for-the-technical-crowd&quot;&gt;For the Technical Crowd&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content Moderation Architecture&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our content moderation system is built on a microservices architecture using Rust for performance and safety. The system processes content through multiple analysis pipelines:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pattern Recognition&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Advanced text analysis for detecting harmful content patterns&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Context Awareness&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Understanding of gaming terminology and SWG-specific language&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real-time Processing&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Sub-second response times for live chat and forum posts&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audit Logging&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Comprehensive logging for transparency and system improvement&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core3 Integration&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Direct integration with SWGEmu server patterns for seamless operation&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Database Architecture &amp;amp; API Services&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#x27;ve established a production-ready database architecture using PostgreSQL with schema-per-service isolation. Key improvements include:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smithy Code Generation&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Type-safe API definitions with automatic Rust SDK generation&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SQLx Integration&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Compile-time SQL verification and schema binding&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Graviton Optimization&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: ARM64-native compilation for cost-effective AWS deployment&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zero-PII Storage&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: User privacy by design with minimal data retention&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automated Migrations&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Database schema updates with zero-downtime deployments&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infrastructure Highlights:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;50+ database migrations&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; establishing core platform schemas&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8 microservices&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; handling authentication, content moderation, user management, and analytics&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3,000+ lines&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; of production Rust code with comprehensive error handling&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automated deployment&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; with rollback capabilities and health monitoring&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-environment&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; testing with staging and production isolation&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;security-compliance&quot;&gt;Security &amp;amp; Compliance&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building on our &quot;Security is Job Zero&quot; philosophy, we&#x27;ve enhanced the platform with:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Error Handling&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Detailed logging without exposing sensitive information&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secrets Management&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Proper credential rotation and access controls&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audit Trails&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Complete activity logging for security and compliance&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Input Validation&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Comprehensive sanitization and validation at all API boundaries&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dependency Management&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Regular security updates and vulnerability scanning&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;looking-ahead&quot;&gt;Looking Ahead&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This foundation enables the next phase of development:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Galaxy API Integration&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Complete Core3 integration for seamless server management&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Galaxy Management Dashboard&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Comprehensive tools for community administrators&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Galaxy Invite Process&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Streamlined onboarding for new galaxy communities&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced Analytics&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Insights into community health and engagement&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Custom Integrations&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: API access for third-party tools and bots&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cross-Galaxy Features&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Optional shared experiences while maintaining community independence&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;ready-for-expanded-beta&quot;&gt;Ready for Expanded Beta&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these core systems in place, we&#x27;re preparing to expand our beta program to include more galaxies and communities. The platform now has the reliability, security, and scalability needed to support real communities with real players.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#x27;re a galaxy owner interested in joining the beta program, or a player wanting to explore what SWGRealms offers, visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.swgrealms.com&quot;&gt;swgrealms.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to get started.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Questions about our content moderation approach or technical architecture? Reach out at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:interested@swgrealms.com&quot;&gt;interested@swgrealms.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Developer Update 002 - Secure, Scalable Registration</title>
        <published>2025-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.swgrealms.com/updates/developer-update-002-secure-scalable-registration/"/>
        <id>https://www.swgrealms.com/updates/developer-update-002-secure-scalable-registration/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://www.swgrealms.com/updates/developer-update-002-secure-scalable-registration/">&lt;p&gt;We&#x27;re excited to announce that SWGRealms now has a complete, production-ready authentication system that prioritizes security while preserving your SWGEmu community history. This update represents a major milestone in our mission to provide a secure, scalable platform for Star Wars Galaxies communities.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;security-is-job-zero&quot;&gt;Security is Job Zero&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At SWGRealms, we believe that &lt;strong&gt;Security is Job Zero&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Too many gaming servers &quot;roll their own security,&quot; which sounds straightforward until a breach occurs and user emails, passwords, and personal data end up on the dark web for $0.01 per user. We&#x27;ve taken a different approach by building on enterprise-grade infrastructure from day one.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;preserving-your-swgemu-legacy&quot;&gt;Preserving Your SWGEmu Legacy&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While security is paramount, we haven&#x27;t forgotten about community. Our authentication system seamlessly integrates with SWGEmu&#x27;s systems to preserve your community history:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Veteran Status&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Your original join date from 2006+ is preserved&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forum Activity&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Post counts and activity timestamps are maintained&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community Identity&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Your legacy username and verification status carry forward&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seamless Migration&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Existing SWGEmu users can sign in with their current credentials&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lets you bring your SWGEmu legacy into SWGRealms without losing years of community history and contributions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-this-means-for-you&quot;&gt;What This Means for You&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For Non-Technical Users:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of our authentication system like a secure bank vault for your gaming identity. Instead of every galaxy owner having to build their own security (like keeping cash under a mattress), we use a professional, heavily-guarded system that&#x27;s designed specifically for protecting user accounts.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you sign in to SWGRealms:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your password never leaves Amazon&#x27;s secure servers&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Galaxy owners only see the information they need to run their communities&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your personal data is protected by the same systems that secure major corporations&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You get one account that works across all galaxies, but each galaxy can&#x27;t see your activity on others&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For Galaxy Owners:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can focus on creating amazing content and building your community instead of worrying about security breaches, password management, or user data protection. The authentication system handles all the complex security requirements automatically, giving you peace of mind and more time for what matters most.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;community-focused-security&quot;&gt;Community-Focused Security&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we see SWGRealms as a place to build community, we also see it as a place to create that community securely and at scale. Our goal is to enable galaxy owners to focus on creative content and players to not sweat the details of how we glue it all together.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security doesn&#x27;t have to come at the expense of community – it can actually strengthen it by building trust and enabling features that wouldn&#x27;t be possible with traditional approaches.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;for-the-technical-crowd&quot;&gt;For the Technical Crowd&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazon Cognito: Enterprise-Grade Authentication&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our authentication system is built on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;aws.amazon.com&#x2F;cognito&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Amazon Cognito&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the same service that powers authentication for millions of applications worldwide. This isn&#x27;t just about convenience – it&#x27;s about leveraging Amazon&#x27;s decades of security expertise and continuous hardening.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Security Benefits:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Separated Authentication&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Your login credentials are completely isolated from game servers and galaxy systems&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduced Attack Surface&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: SWGRealms never stores your passwords or sensitive personal information&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Managed UI Protection&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Amazon&#x27;s hardened login pages prevent clickjacking, credential theft, and other common attacks&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enterprise Compliance&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Built-in support for security standards and regulatory requirements&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Future-Ready&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Native support for multi-factor authentication, social logins, and advanced security features&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Implementation:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#x27;ve implemented a modern OAuth 2.0 flow with JWT tokens, custom attribute mapping, and automated user migration. The system uses AWS Lambda for serverless authentication processing, with comprehensive logging and monitoring. All user data is encrypted in transit and at rest, with proper key management and rotation.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;built-for-scale&quot;&gt;Built for Scale&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SWGRealms is designed to support thousands of galaxies and tens of thousands of concurrent players if the community so desires. Our authentication infrastructure scales automatically, ensuring consistent performance whether we&#x27;re serving a handful of beta users or a thriving universe of communities.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By the Numbers:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1,200+ lines of code&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; across authentication components&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8 custom user attributes&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; for preserving SWGEmu history&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3 integrated systems&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Static site, authentication server, and play platform&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 deployment environments&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; with automated testing and rollback capabilities&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1 unified identity&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; across all galaxies in the SWGRealms universe&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;looking-forward&quot;&gt;Looking Forward&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This authentication foundation enables exciting future features:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-Factor Authentication&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; for enhanced security&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Login Integration&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; (Discord, GitHub, etc.)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced Permission Systems&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; for galaxy management&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cross-Galaxy Features&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; while maintaining privacy boundaries&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API Access&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; for third-party integrations&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;ready-for-beta-testing&quot;&gt;Ready for Beta Testing&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complete authentication system is now live! SWGEmu community members can &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.swgrealms.com&#x2F;register&#x2F;&quot;&gt;register for SWGRealms&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with their existing credentials and explore the platform while preserving their community history.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#x27;re excited to see what the community thinks of this foundation as we continue building toward our full platform launch.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have questions about our security approach or want to learn more about the technical implementation? Contact us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:interested@swgrealms.com&quot;&gt;interested@swgrealms.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Development Update 001 - July 2025</title>
        <published>2025-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.swgrealms.com/updates/site-development-updated-001/"/>
        <id>https://www.swgrealms.com/updates/site-development-updated-001/</id>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since the project is currently a one person show, I&#x27;ve been focused on setting up as much automation as possible while building the foundation for what SWGRealms will become. This update covers the progression from initial concept through early implementation.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;</summary>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Beta Development Update - January 2025</title>
        <published>2025-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.swgrealms.com/updates/beta-development-update/"/>
        <id>https://www.swgrealms.com/updates/beta-development-update/</id>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&#x27;re excited to share that SWGRealms has officially entered the private beta development phase! Our team is working diligently to build the managed hosting platform that will eliminate technical barriers for Star Wars Galaxies communities, with our launch partners helping validate the platform design.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;</summary>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
